Curriculum Vitae

Clients I have worked for and clients which use/ have used my services

Lloyd's of London lloyds.com

British Red Cross redcross.org.uk

Marks and Spencer yourgreenidea.co.uk

Sony Pictures sonypictures.com

Freud Communications freud.com

Petro Canada www.petro-canada.ca

Towergate Insurance www.towergate.co.uk

t: 0754 081 7008 w: http://the-taylors.org t: http://twitter.com/davetayls

address: 19 Chipstead Ave, Thornton Heath, Surrey, CR7 7DJ linkedIn: http://uk.linkedin.com/in/davidtaylorlondon

I am a disciplined and passionate front end web developer / graphic designer with over seven years experience working with clients across a range of technologies.

I approach tasks with intelligent analysis and creative flair, capitalising on available information to produce tangible results and clear benefits within deadlines.

I make full use of the latest technologies to produce user-centric, cross-browser, validated HTML/ CSSwebsites progressively enhanced using JavaScript. I have extensive experience building .net web-applications and controls.

I get a real buzz working at the forefront of my field researching new developments as they emerge and contributing to the developer community.

I have extensive experience using open source JavaScript library iQuery and working with AJAX applications.

I am an experienced team leader and team player.

Experience

July 2009 to Present - Aqueduct

(Creative Agency Specialising in Brand, Advertising, Digital and Design) **Clerkenwell, London** (Senior Front-End Developer)

I was brought in to the agency to start and build a Front-End development team where purely freelancers where used in the past. Tasked with setting standards, overseeing code quality and putting these in to practice. With my background in Design and Back-End experience; I am the linchpin between the back end team, design team and front end team. Understanding the relationships between each; I make them work more effectively together. Here are some key achievements from this role:

- Set the framework and built the new **Lloyd's of London** website at www.lloyds.com. This project spanned the corporate website and the migration of five in house web applications.
- Set the framework and built the new British Red Cross corporate (www.redcross.org.uk) and Red Cross Training sites.
- JavaScript build and management of freelance code for Marks and Spencer's Your Green Idea microsite www.yourgreenidea.co.uk.
- Feedbackfrom my team: David is a team player and always thrives to improve himself and the team's output as a whole, he influences people without being pedant and is always full of new ideas; he is pragmatic, skilful and has great attention to detail, he has the same goal as the rest of the team which is to deliver work we are proud of.

Feb 2005 to July 2009 - Qdos Computer Consultants Ltd

Croydon, Surrey (Design Consultant / Senior Front-End Developer)

Head of design and web front end. I worked within a team to accomplish web based application projects, corporate websites, e-commerce solutions, branding services, print design for charities and SME's. Here are some key achievements from this role:

- Produced SharePoint applications for international communications company Freud Communications (www.freud.com) to manage daily press coverage and event organising.
- Head of design and user front end on ClearBUILD©considered by a panel of industry specialists at the InterBuild 2007 building show to be the second most innovative product of 2007. ClearBUILD©is an extremely user friendly and simplistic application designed to interface with construction site based staff, who traditionally have limited IT skills. www.simplyclearsolutions.com
- Usability and interface design on training needs web-application for petrochemicals company (Petro Canada) which facilitated ease of use and led to effective training.

July 2002 to Feb 2005 - Mime Graphics

Croydon, Surrey (Creative Director)

I began working as a freelance designer in a partnership after college with the view to building a strong portfolio of work. The quality of my work and the client portfolio I developed successfully positioned the company to attract a merger with a larger company. Here are some key achievements from this role:

- Long term, key account management and client relationship building from both large and small businesses.
- Successful utilisation of resources to produce sustainable results within deadlines.
- Experience in pre-press and dealing with printers both lithographic and digital.

Skills and Qualifications

Programming skill set:

JavaScript Custom framework building,

jQuery Framework including jQuery Plugins

QUnit JavaScript testing library

isLint verified and automated in continuous integration

isDocToolkit JavaScript documentation builder

Microsoft Ajax Framework,

HTML XHTML 4.0 Strict, (X)HTML 5, Written by hand, written to be integrated within CMSsystems

CSS css3, Written by hand. Design building for mobile devices, screen and print

Selenium Remote Control and IDE

VB,C#.net Websites, Windows applications, .net Web Controls, SharePoint

XML XML data files, data transfer (SOAP), configurations

XSL/ XSLT SharePoint XSLtransformations for data web parts into custom displays
SharePoint Custom applications: uploading and viewing of daily press coverage and the

organisation of attendees to various events. WebParts, Web Services

SQL Database design, select statements, joins, stored procedures

Methodologies

Agile: Scrum, Kanban

CMS

Sitecore, EPIServer, Wordpress, Involved in design of custom .net CMS solution

Applications skill set:

Visual Studio, Eclipse, Aptana, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver

Source ControlContinuous IntegrationSubversion, Git, Visual Source SafenAnt, CruiseControl.net

Server experience E-Commerce

IIS, SQL Server 2005, Server R3, Microsoft Exchange Ptotx

Other relevant work

- Juxtapo Front End Tools: www.juxtapo.net, In browser tools for overlays and auto refresh including a plug-in API with available extensions integrating with Google Docs and Qunit.
- I maintain an active blog aimed mainly at front-end developers.
- SJS(http://github.com/davetayls/sjs) is a very simple server side JavaScript framework which will work across various platforms (eg Mozilla Rhino and Microsoft cscript)
- I currently manage a team of over 30 musicians at my local church. My duties include people management, recruitment and training, setting targets and encouraging musicians to reach their full potential.
- From 1999 2006 I was the lead singer and guitarist in the rock band Life Support Sound. I was responsible for gig bookings, brand and marketing via leaflets, flyers and our website.

Qualifications

Master CIW Designer (2006): CIW Certified Internet Web Professional Program. www.ciwcertified.com

BTEC Diploma, Foundation Studies in Art and Design (2001): London College of Printing (School of Graphic Design)

A Levels in Computing (A), Electronics(A), Art (C) (2000): John Ruskin Sixth Form College